# IRINA SARATOVSKAYA



# **Junior Front End Developer**

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Date of birth: 26.02.1986
Nationality: Russian

Current residence: Moscow, Russia

#### **CONTACT DETAILS:**

- +7 925 152 2219, +66 9 4535 9849 (WA)
- ☑ saratovskaya.business@gmail.com
- (e) www.irinasaratovskaya.com

# **PROFILE:**

Result-oriented professional with 13 years of experience in various areas, including IT, Blockchain and Fintech projects, working in business development, sales, software development, software testing and translation & localization (English, Korean and Russian). I am a quick learner who can absorb new ideas and find effective solutions. I have a passion for programming, and I have been honing my skills in side projects under the mentoring of a senior Silicon Valley developer.

# **EDUCATION:**

2003-2008: Russian State Social University (Russia, Moscow)

Department of foreign languages

**Major:** Theory and methods of teaching foreign languages and cultures (English, Korean).

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# **Front End Development (Freelance)**

- Working on various small projects
- Part-time internship at a Nutrition Technology startup

## **Translation and Localization (Freelance)**

09/2008 - 03/2020

03/2020 - current

I work with five translation/localization agencies in Russia.

- Areas of translation: IT, cryptocurrency, Blockchain, Fintech, marketing
   PR, legal, accounting and finance, medicine, etc.
- UI localization of websites, apps, online games, etc.

#### AVA Software (IT startup), Singapore

08/2019 - 03/2020

# Sales & Business Development Manager

#### Responsibilities:

- Promoting and selling innovative IT products and services in Southeast Asia, Europe, and the USA (B2B).
- Market research and sales strategy development.
- Assisting in testing new software features.

# Key achievements:

I helped to plan and coordinate the development and launch of the company's flagship product, business proposals and communication strategy to attract the first clients, and build partnerships with several major companies in the industry.

## CFS Digital (Blockchain, crypto projects), Estonia

08/2017 - 08/2019

#### **Market Specialist & Business Development Manager**

#### Responsibilities:

- Turnkey solutions, ICOs, promotion of Blockchain and Fintech products and services on the global stage, including marketing & PR, community management, IR.
- Translation & localization (English, Korean, and Russian): websites, UI, presentations, Whitepaper, content for blogs, etc.; software testing.

# **ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:**

**08/2019 – current: Front End Development** Self-education & professional mentoring.

# 10/2010: The National Institute of Korean Language (Korea)

Educational Program for Experts in Korean Studies.

**07/2007 – 08/2007: Gwangju University (Korea)** Korean language training and culture experience program.

# 06/2006 – 09/2006: Changwon National University (Korea)

Korean language training and culture experience program.

# **LANGUAGES:**

- √ English (fluent)
- √ Korean (fluent)
- √ Russian (native)

#### Key achievements:

I helped multiple Blockchain startups adapt their products and services for foreign markets (SEA, Russia, and Europe) and raise over 50,000 BTC on ICOs.

# Asia Marine, Ltd. (Luxury Yacht charters), Thailand

11/2016 - 04/2017

# Sales Manager

# Responsibilities:

- Selling Luxury Yacht charters and coordinating activities within the charter division.
- Preparation of promotional materials, managing the company's website. Translation of documents, websites, brochures, etc.

#### Key achievements:

I attracted the Russian market by establishing partnerships with eight major Russian travel agencies and luxury hotels and villas in Phuket. This provided a continuous flow of customers and therefore increased sales by 30%.

# VCP Tour Co., Ltd. (Tourist services), Thailand

05/2014 - 10/2016

# **Sales and Marketing manager**

#### Responsibilities:

- Selling catamaran private charters & group tours, transfers, spa packages, etc., and developing and maintaining relationships with tour suppliers, hotels, car rental agencies, shops, etc.
- Assisting in developing the company's online booking system and website (translation & localization, testing, creating and updating content).

#### Key achievements:

I helped to localize the products and services: booking system, website, etc., and adapt for and attract the Russian market with which the company had never worked before.

# Nuga Medical (Korean medical equipment), Russia

10/2012 - 03/2014

#### Senior marketing manager/Translator (English, Korean, Russian)

## Responsibilities:

- Interpreting (simultaneous, consecutive): lectures, dealer meetings, seminars, conferences. Translation: educational materials (medical field), letters, agreements, etc.
- Organization of dealer conferences (Russia, Turkey), interaction with Russian and foreign travel agencies, development of ad materials.

## Key achievements:

I organized and successfully held several large conferences (1000+ participants) in Russia and Turkey, education seminars (250+ people) in Russia.

# Daehong Communications (Marketing & PR), Russia

10/2007 - 09/2012

# Account manager/Translator (English, Korean, Russian)

#### Responsibilities:

- Translation and interpreting (company documents, presentations, research results, marketing materials, meetings, conferences).
- Preparation and realization of advertising campaigns.

# Key achievements:

I helped increase sales by launching several large advertising campaigns for our major clients.

# **PROGRAMMING SKILLS:**

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Node.js
- HTML, CSS

# **TECHNOLOGY TOOLS:**

- MS Office
- SmartCAT
- MemoQ
- Git, npm

# **COLLABORATION TOOLS:**

- Jira, Trello
- Asana
- Zoho
- Slack, Zoom
- Pipedrive

# **PORTFOLIO:**

#### Github profile:

https://github.com/IrinaSaratovskaya